[Latin music playing]
(Jill Beauchamp)I believe that our program here
at Washtenaw Community Collegein Culinary and Hospitality
is the program of choicein southeastern Michigan.
I know that's pretty bold,but I just think that
if a student wants to learnboth theory and practice,
we will allow for that.
The students are anotherhuge strength of our program.
(Andrew Willis)I've worked in restaurants
on and offpretty much my whole life.
I've worked in the backof the house, the front
of the house, I've doneother things in my career
and just came back towhat I love.
(Cassondra Curtis)I feel that I'm getting a lot
out of this program.
Not only some great friendsand a great education,
great experience, but justmemories that I can have
for the rest of my life.
(Jill Beauchamp)Garrett's Restaurant is a full
service laboratory classroom,where the students learn
the art of giving good servicewhile taking the course work
along with it.
(Cassondra Curtis)You actually get to run
a restaurant.
I know a lot of colleges thathave culinary classes, but when
I tell them about ours,they're like,
"Wow, that would be so cool."
[Latin music playing]
(Zachary Hintalla)For the past two years,
my most memorable experienceshave both dealt with working
at Mardi Gras.
It's a blast each year.
(Carol Deinzer)Mardi Gras is
an annual fundraiser at theCollege for the
general scholarship fund.
It's a huge opportunityfor our students.
Not only do they get real-lifeexperience with serving
hundred's of people, they alsoget the opportunity to work
with chefs from the outside,which just is invaluable.
(Jill Beauchamp)The most important factor,
of course, is the instruction.
I think we havetop-notch instructors,
both full time and part time.
(Cassondra Curtis)My instructors are actually
very wonderful.
They are reallydown-to-earth people,
and it makes it so much easierto ask questions and be open
and even to be a little sillyat times.
(Andrew Willis)The instructors are just
relentless.
They're so tough.I mean, I can't...
I'm just kidding.
(Terri Herrera)I feel I have to get in
with the studentsinstead of standing
over lecturing.
I have to do it,be involved with them.
And I feel as though Iget the most out of my students
when I teach that way.
(Paul McPherson)I think what's important
about our programis some of the opportunities
that it presents itself,not only a few
of our specialty classes,but the individualized attention
that our students get here -the counseling and the advice
and just the dedicationfrom faculty.
(Terri Herrera)I still feel as though I'm part
of their lives because, hey,I talked to you,
I trained you.I feel like they're my children.
It's just a passion that I havefor teaching.
(Paul McPherson)There's always an excitement
about being a chefor being a pastry chef
and being involvedin a very active industry.
(Gena Parker)I feel that I will be sought
after I'm donewith this program
because I've learned so much.
I have qualities,I have confidence in myself
because of the programand what I've learned.
(Zachary Hintalla)The instruction here
has definitely prepared meto move on to what I'd like
to do later on in life:to run my own restaurant.
(Jill Beauchamp)When I see a student
find a careerthat they're
passionate about,that is the
greatest source of pride for me.